all right this video is going to be on
the floor press but how how to do
specifically how to do the floor press
without a spotter it's uh kind of funny
I I was uh doing some research on the
history of the bench press and uh before
the bench ever came out before we
actually used benches they used to have
pressing competitions and it was the
floor press but you could kind of lift
it any way so people had different
techniques some would be more strict
some would kind of uh get a huge Arch
and do like a bridge press and then some
people would toss it up they called it a
belly toss but it's what I think it is I
don't know where they set up with the
bar if it was on their bellies or on
their hips but it was like a glute
Bridge an explosive glute bridge where
they lock it out
overhead anyway um I've been doing this
for a while and I think a lot of people
don't really know like if I'm at a
CrossFit type gym and they don't have
any benches well how can I get a good
pressing workout one thing about the
that I like about the floor press is
research shows that you know the sticky
point is right in here this range you
get a huge passive contribution from you
know elastic contribution from the
stretch reflex to get the bar off your
chest but when that when that when those
contributions and and the neural you
know the stretch reflex and the elastic
tissue uh transfer run out then you're
all on your own now you're relying on
concentric strength that's why the floor
press helps a lot of people get stronger
so uh you can still get a good very good
pressing workout even if you're in a gym
that doesn't have a bench press and I
and I'm going to show you how to do it
so um you know you can still go heavy as
long as you have strong glutes so just
like you're going to do a barbell glute
bridge line up the weight iine line up
right at my hips this doesn't have a pad
a pad here but that's all right cuz this
is
lightweight not nearly as heav as I can
glute Bridge Okay I'm going to get into
position and then from here I just do an
explosive
Bridge um well I have two options I can
do an explosive bridge and catch
overhead or I can just kind of rock it
back in a position this is the way I
like to do so I'll show you I just kind
of come up get it in the position and
then from here what I like to do is each
rep I will rest a second and get a pause
so from
here come down now I'll pause for a
couple seconds one 2
3 come
up one 2
3 on now from here I just drop the
weight down I'm come back out so this is
a way to do the floor press without a
spotter you don't have to have someone
hand it to you I can get it into
position using uh similar uh to glute
Bridge motion and uh this way I can
still stay strong at the bench press
exercise even if I'm not bench pressing
so give it a try let me know what you
think